Guide to the Self-Study Steering Committee Records, 1965-1998 UA.03.02.0005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Self-Study Steering Committee records
1965-1998
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Self-Study Steering Committee
UA.03.02.0005
4 Linear Feet
Collection includes Duke University's self-study reports submitted to the Southern Association for Colleges and Schools in 1965, 1976, 1988 and 1998, as well as surrounding correspondence and schedules.
4000 Items
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
The Self-Study Steering Committee Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1973-1999.
Historical Note
A committee is convened once a decade to carry out a self-study of the University for its re-accreditation by the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools (S.A.C.S). The committee has been appointed by the President and the Provost. S.A.C.S. was the name used for the reports until 1976. Beginning in 1988, the name "Self-Study Steering Committee" was used.
Under the leadership of John Carlisle Kilgo, Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) became one of the founding members of S.A.C.S., at that time called the Association of Colleges and Preparatory Schools of the Southern States.
Collection Overview
Contains self-reports from various schools, departments, libraries and facilities at Duke, published in 1965, 1976, 1988 and 1998, and submitted to the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools and the Steering Committee. Also includes correspondence and schedules relating to campus visits made by the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools visiting committees.
The Library cataloged reports under several different call numbers.
Related Material
Balancing the Roles of the Research University: A Self-Study Presented by Duke University to the Commission on Colleges, S.A.C.S.
University Archives. Duke University.
Turning a Chapter: A Self Study of the Perkins Library System.
University Archives. Duke University.
Duke University Self Study: Crossing Boundaries, Interdisciplinary Planning for the Nineties.
University Archives. Duke University.
Continuing Self-Evaluation: Developing the Process: A Report for the Commission on Colleges of the S.A.C.S.
University Archives. Duke University.
Report of Self-Study: The Divinity School.
University Archives. Duke University.
Duke University -- History -- 20th century; Committees -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.; Duke University. Self-Study Steering Committee; Duke University. Self-Study Steering Committee
- 1965, 3 boxes
  - Trinity College Self-Study Report (Box 1)
  - Manual for the Institutional Self-Study and Periodic Visitation Program Correspondence Re: Oct. 1965 Visit (Box 1)
  - Memos and Correspondence Re: Visits to Biological Sciences, Zoology, Marine Lab (Box 1)
  - Self-Study Report (Box 1)
  - Self-Study: Memos and Information Regarding (Box 1)
  - 1965 Self-Studies (Box 2)
    - Aerospace Studies, Naval Science (Box 2)
    - Physical Education (Box 2)
    - Humanities (Art, Classical Studies, English, Germanic Languages, Music, Philosophy, Religion, Romance Languages) (Box 2)
    - Natural Sciences (Botany, Chemistry, Geology, Mathematics, Physics, Zoology) (Box 2)
    - Special Programs (Aging, Marine Lab, Commonwealth Studies) (Box 2)
  - 1965 Self Studies (cont'd): (Box 3)
    - Trinity College (Box 3)
    - Summer Session (Box 3)
    - Library (Box 3)
    - Social Sciences (Economics, Education, History, Political Science, Psychology) (Box 3)
    - Engineering (Box 3)
    - Woman's College (Box 3)
    - Divinity School (Box 3)
    - Law School (Box 3)
    - Social Science Council (Box 3)
    - Duke Hospital (Box 3)
- 1976, 3 boxes
  - Duke University Report of Fifth Year Reaffirmation of Institutional Self-Study: 1971 (Box 4)
  - Visit Schedule, Religious Life Report: 1976 (Box 4)
  - Continuing Self-Evaluation: Developing the Process: 1976 (Box 4)
  - Continuing Self-Evaluation: Developing the Process - Student Affairs and Services: 1976 (Box 5)
    - Humanities (Box 5)
    - Law School, Divinity School, Nursing (Box 5)
    - Library Services, Library Annual Report, Engineering (Box 5)
    - Business and Finance (Box 5)
    - Interdepartmental (Box 5)
    - Natural Sciences (Box 5)
  - "Developing the Process": Self-Studies, 1976 (cont'd) (Box 6)
    - Materials for October 1976 Visit (Box 6)
    - Materials Given to S.A.C.S. Visiting Committee on Arrival, 1976 (Box 6)
    - Black Studies, Institutional Advancement (Box 6)
    - Alumni Affairs, Medical and Allied Health, Forestry and Environmental (Box 6)
    - Marine Lab, Aerospace Studies and Naval Science, Anatomy and Health Education (Box 6)
    - Athletic Association (Box 6)
    - Social Science (Box 6)
- 1988, 1 boxes
  - Duke University Self-Study Report Appendix, 1988 (Box 7)
  - Self-Study: "Crossing Boundaries: Interdisciplinary Planning for the 90s", 1988 (Box 7)
  - S.A.C.S.: Duke Reaccredidation Report, 1988 (Box 7)
- 1997, 1 boxes
  - Compliance with Criteria for Accreditation Commission on Colleges, SACS, 1997 (3 folders) (Box 8)